

BRIAN NJOGU

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL DETAILS

I am an experienced software engineer that leverages the power of the available programming languages (preferring JavaScript) to build state-of-the-art, easy to use, user-friendly websites and applications. I believe in cooperation and team work, while quickly learning about and embracing new technologies as needed. I am a keen listener and love to take on challenges head-on.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- 1. Creating wireframes and mockups.
- 2. Reproducing designs into code.
- 3. Integrating pages with related APIs.
- 4. Making structured code responsive.
- 5. Implementing beautiful UI designs.
- 6. Ascertaining user experience (UX) is seamless.
- 7. Testing and debugging built products.
- 8. Database management.
- 9. Server side scripting and all things backend.
- 10. Creating and maintaining APIs.
- 11. Scaling infrastructure in response to growth.

FIND ME AT:

Cell: +254 742 934 822 Email: briancanspit@gmail.com

Website: https://njogu.co.ke

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/briancanspit Github: https://github.com/briancanspit

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Diversely qualified software developer trained in building real, production worthy websites, mobile and desktop applications. Experience in the JAM stack and highly responsive to the delivery of fast and efficient software that solves modern day problems as per client specification. Ensures compliance with client/company policies and regulations in carrying out job functions. Embracing towards new technology stacks and always willing to learn.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Technical University of Kenya

2017 - 2022 (expected)

Currently pursuing a Bachelor's of Technology degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GRANULAR IT (LTD) KENYA

January, 2020 - Present

Software Engineer - full stack development

Kenyan Wall Street

January, 2020 - February, 2020

Front End Developer - cross platform mobile app development

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Firebase
- SASS
- GatsbyJS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- AWS
- jQuery
- Netlify
- React
- Git

- React Native

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led the team of developers that won in a hackathon held by Granular IT on the 29th of October, 2019 (React).
- Coded a cross platform desktop music player application from scratch in JavaScript using Node Webkit (NW.js).
- Built a desktop Twitter client that allows you to filter the latest tweets on search, as well as posting tweets at will (React).
- Built and open sourced two cyber security projects that demonstrate the impact a malicious attacker can make (Python/PHP).
- Built a mobile application for Android/iOS for weather updates (React Native).